# Fabrizio Cara

### **Contacts**

E-mail: fcaraengineer@gmail.com

Phone: +39 3406031268

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/fabriziocara

Website: <u>fcaraengineer.github.io</u> Github: <u>github.com/fcaraengineer</u>

Google Scholar: <a href="mailto:scholar:google.com/citations?user=0UIIMggAAAAJ&hl=it">scholar:google.com/citations?user=0UIIMggAAAAJ&hl=it</a>

# **Summary**

A fast-learning and technology enthusiastic person, I completed my academic studies in Computer Engineering with honors. For two years, I have been working on Computer Security research projects. I enjoy organizing and exchanging ideas to develop an approach to achieve the most significant outcomes for the team. For the future, I am looking for new experiences and opportunities to improve myself and my knowledge in the fields of Computer Security and Software Engineering.

# **Experiences**

• **Research Assistant – PhD** (2018 – now)

<u>Course:</u> Computer Engineering <u>Research Field</u>: Computer Security

<u>Location</u>: University of Cagliari, Cagliari, Italy <u>Laboratory</u>: PRALab (<u>pralab.diee.unica.it</u>)

Supervisor: Prof. Giorgio Giacinto

• **Research Internship** (12/2019 – 06/2020)

Research Field: Computer Security (Internet of Things) & Software Engineering

Location: Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, Georgia, Stati Uniti

Laboratory: Astrolavos Lab (astrolavos.gatech.edu)

Supervisor: Prof. Manos Antonakakis

• **Research Scholarship** (01/2018 – 07/2018)

<u>Title</u>: Study and development of intrusion detection techniques on X86 and Mobile platforms

through the analysis of logs and codes.

<u>Location</u>: University of Cagliari, Cagliari, Italy <u>Laboratory</u>: PRALab (<u>pralab.diee.unica.it</u>)

### **Education**

• Master's degree in Telecommunications Engineering (Internet Engineering) (2016 – 2018)

Location: University of Cagliari, Cagliari, Italy

Relevant Corsework: Operating Systems, Computer Security, Machine Learning, Smart

Housing, Internet of Things, Computer Architectures, Embedded Systems, Information Theory and Coding, Innovative Architectures and Applications in the Internet, Mobile Networks Final Grade: 110/110 magna cum laude

• Bachelor's degree in Electrical and Electronics Engineering (Computer Engineering curriculum) (2013 – 2016)

Location: University of Cagliari, Cagliari, Italy

<u>Relevant Corsework</u>: Computer Architectures, Communication Networks, Signal Theory, Databases, Digital System Design, Software Engineering, Internet, Web development, Object-

Oriented Programming Languages

Final Grade: 105/110

#### **Publications**

• On the Feasibility of Adversarial Sample Creation Using the Android System API

Authors: Fabrizio Cara, Michele Scalas, Giorgio Giacinto, Davide Maiorca

Editor: Multidisciplinary Digital Publishing Institute (MDPI)

Date: 09/2020

• PowerDrive: Accurate De-obfuscation and Analysis of PowerShell Malware

Authors: Denis Ugarte, Davide Maiorca, Fabrizio Cara, Giorgio Giacinto

Editor: Springer, Cham

Conference: International Conference on Detection of Intrusions and Malware, and

Vulnerability Assessment (DIMVA)

Date: 06/2019

#### Skills

Scale: beginner, intermediate, advanced, expert

- Programming Languages:
  - Python: advanced
    HTML: advanced
    SQL: advanced
    JAVA: intermediate
    CSS: intermediate
  - **JAVASCRIPT**: beginner
  - C: beginner
- Advanced knowledge of Windows, Linux and Android
- Intermediate knowledge of machine learning algorithms
- Advanced knowledge of network traffic analysis and reverse engineering

# Languages

Italian: native speakerEnglish: advanced level